<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Apache Wicket</title>
 <link href="http://wicket.apache.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://wicket.apache.org/"/>
 <updated>2012-09-05T18:20:37+02:00</updated>
 <id>http://wicket.apache.org/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Apache Wicket</name>
   <email>dev@wicket.apache.org</email>
 </author>
 
 
 <entry>
   <title>Apache Wicket v6.0.0 released</title>
   <link href="http://wicket.apache.org/2012/09/05/wicket-6.0.0-released.html"/>
   <updated>2012-09-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://wicket.apache.org/2012/09/05/wicket-6.0.0-released</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;With great pleasure we announce the availability of Apache Wicket 6.0.0&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Martijn Dashorst, Vice President, Apache Wicket&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apache Wicket v6.0.0 is the 6th major release of the popular open source Java web framework. Numerous enhancements make Apache Wicket v6.0.0 a solid choice for web development:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Out-of-the box JQuery integration&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Complete control over AJAX requests&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Improved event registration in browsers&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Support for large datasets in components&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dependency management for client side javascript libraries&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Experimental support for websockets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release is available from the &lt;a href='http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/wicket/6.0.0'&gt;usual download location (wicket-6.0.0)&lt;/a&gt;, or available through the Maven Central repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional features include a customizable client-side API, improved feedback messages, correct packaging for OSGi compatibility and improved initialization of plugins. Highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Java 6 required - This release moves the minimum required Java version to Java 6. This means that Wicket applications running on earlier Java versions meaning to upgrade, also need to upgrade their Java runtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revamped Wicket AJAX now leverages JQuery - Wicket&amp;#8217;s custom AJAX JavaScript library has been re-implemented using JQuery. This makes it easier to integrate JQuery plugins into Wicket applications. With the new AJAX implementation it is possible to provide your own version of JQuery should the need arise, or even to replace the whole Wicket client side AJAX implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AJAX Attributes - With the new and improved AJAX implementation, you can alter any aspect of an AJAX request through AjaxRequestAttributes. For example you can specify that the request should be executed using POST instead of GET, or that the AJAX request should be multi-part, etc. See the migration guide or the JavaDoc of AjaxRequestAttributes for all possible options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browser event registration replaces inline events - Wicket now uses JavaScript event registration instead of inline attributes for AJAX components. This enables multiple event listeners to be attached to a markup tag, cleans up the rendered markup considerably and reduces the amount of generated markup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IDataProvider now uses long instead of int - The &lt;code&gt;IDataProvider&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; interface and implementations now use long instead of int for index and size parameters to better line up with the Java Persistence API and other persistency frameworks. Big data is now possible with Wicket!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;${label}&lt;/code&gt; replaces &lt;code&gt;${input}&lt;/code&gt; in feedback messages - Previous Wicket versions used the input that was provided by users in error messages when validations failed. This led to error messages like &amp;#8220;1234a is not a valid number&amp;#8221;. In Wicket 6 the feedback messages use the label of the invalid form component instead. You can set the label by calling setLabel() on the form component. If no label is provided, Wicket defaults to displaying the component identifier. This changes the error message to &amp;#8220;Phonenumber is not a valid number&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources can declare dependencies - It is now much easier to create resource contributions with dependencies, for example a JQuery plugin can declare a dependency on JQuery and other resources such as embedded style sheets. Users of such resources don’t have to provide these dependencies themselves, and the dependencies are linked in the appropriate order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Packaged resources will use minimized version automatically - When a minimized JavaScript resource is available (filename.min.js – add the .min part to the filename before the extension), Wicket will automatically use the minimized version when running in deployment mode, while using the non-minimized version for development mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OSGi compatible packaging - Wicket&amp;#8217;s packaging has been made compatible with OSGi bundles by moving some classes to different packages. The full list can be found in our migration guide. This makes it much easier to deploy Wicket applications in an OSGi environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experimental websocket implementations - This release also includes two experimental websocket implementations: one using Atmosphere as a bridge for browsers and containers that don&amp;#8217;t support websockets natively and one for containers and browsers that have native websocket support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complete set of changes is available in the migration guide at &lt;a href='http://s.apache.org/wicket-6.0-migration'&gt;http://s.apache.org/wicket-6.0-migration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='availability_and_oversight'&gt;Availability and Oversight&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Apache products, Apache Wicket v6.0.0 is released under the Apache License v2.0, and is overseen by a self-selected team of active contributors to the project. A Project Management Committee (PMC) guides the Project&amp;#8217;s day-to-day operations, including community development and product releases. Apache Wicket source code, documentation, and related resources are available at http://wicket.apache.org/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Apache&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Wicket&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;Apache Wicket&amp;#8221;, and &amp;#8220;ApacheCon&amp;#8221; are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation. All other brands and trademarks are the property of their respective owners.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wicket 1.4.21 released</title>
   <link href="http://wicket.apache.org/2012/09/05/wicket-1.4.21-released.html"/>
   <updated>2012-09-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://wicket.apache.org/2012/09/05/wicket-1.4.21-released</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is 21st release of the Wicket 1.4.x series. This is also the last release of the 1.4.x series, rounding up the remaining bugfixes. No further releases will happen in this branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf/wicket/repo?p=wicket.git;a=shortlog;h=refs/tags/release/wicket-1.4.21'&gt;Git tag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12310561&amp;amp;version=12320171'&gt;Changelog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To use in Maven:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='xml'&gt;&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;org.apache.wicket&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;wicket&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;1.4.21&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the &lt;a href='http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/wicket/1.4.21'&gt;full distribution&lt;/a&gt; (including source)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wicket 1.5.8 released</title>
   <link href="http://wicket.apache.org/2012/08/24/wicket-1.5.8-released.html"/>
   <updated>2012-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://wicket.apache.org/2012/08/24/wicket-1.5.8-released</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the eighth maintenance release of the Wicket 1.5.x series. This release brings over 45 bug fixes and improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf/wicket/repo?p=wicket.git;a=shortlog;h=refs/tags/release/wicket.1.5.8'&gt;Git tag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12310561&amp;amp;version=12321662'&gt;Changelog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To use in Maven:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='xml'&gt;&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;org.apache.wicket&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;wicket-core&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;1.5.8&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the &lt;a href='http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/wicket/1.5.8'&gt;full distribution&lt;/a&gt; (including source)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wicket 6.0.0-beta3 released</title>
   <link href="http://wicket.apache.org/2012/07/16/wicket-6.0.0-beta3-released.html"/>
   <updated>2012-07-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://wicket.apache.org/2012/07/16/wicket-6.0.0-beta3-released</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Wicket team is proud to announce the third beta release of the Wicket 6.x series. This release is an intermediary release just before we give you 6.0.0 final.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no more planned API breaks but if you find something that can be made better now it the time to discuss it! The next planned release is 6.0.0 final, so speak now or forever be silenced (or learn to live with it until 7.0.0 comes out).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any feedback about the new features, their implementation and their documentation is very welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id='new_and_noteworthy_in_600beta3'&gt;New and Noteworthy in 6.0.0-beta3&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTA BENE:&lt;/strong&gt; the use of modules that are marked experimental, by being part of the sub module &amp;#8216;wicket-experimental&amp;#8217;, are really that: experimental. These modules can change, disappear or blow up your computer without notice and you really use/depend on them at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='wicket_native_websockets'&gt;Wicket Native Websockets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;strong&gt;experimental&lt;/strong&gt; module has been added to Wicket 6 - Wicket Native WebSocket. This module adds support for using HTML5 WebSockets as you may use Ajax in your Wicket applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you have to do is to add a WebSocketBehavior to your page and from there on you can receive messages from the clients and push messages back to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href='https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/x/0vSoAQ'&gt;our wiki&lt;/a&gt; you may find the documentation and a link to a demo application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If something is not clear feel free to ask your question in the mailing lists and we will improve the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='wicket_bootstrap'&gt;Wicket Bootstrap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;experimental&lt;/strong&gt; modules now contain a new module for integration with Twitter&amp;#8217;s Bootstrap. Currently this module only provides a central way of using the Bootstrap resources. In the future we will provide proper components and behaviors for the Bootstrap concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use this new &lt;strong&gt;experimental&lt;/strong&gt; module, add this to your pom:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.apache.wicket&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;wicket-bootstrap&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;0.1&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add Bootstrap support to your pages, add this in the &lt;code&gt;renderHead&lt;/code&gt; method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@Override
public void renderHead(IHeaderResponse response) {
    super.renderHead(response);

    Bootstrap.renderHead(response);
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will render a dependency to the Twitter bootstrap CSS and JS files, including the required dependency to JQuery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='new_wicket_examples'&gt;New Wicket Examples&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have started an effort to revamp the tried and tested Wicket Examples and bring them into 2012. The new examples are located in the &lt;strong&gt;experimental&lt;/strong&gt; module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is currently a copy of Twitter Bootstrap&amp;#8217;s design but with Wicket specific filling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can test the examples by running the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wicket-examples-jar/src/test/java/Start.java&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;class in the default package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The examples will feature a component reference with typical use cases, full examples such as Hello, World, and descriptions of the code in play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='wicket_atmosphere'&gt;Wicket Atmosphere&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wicket Atmosphere in the experimental modules has seen an upgrade of the Atmosphere dependency to 1.0.0-beta3. This has caused an incompatibility with Jetty 7.6.3 (used with Wicket and the examples). To mitigate this, you need to override either:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the dependency on Jetty to 8.1.3 or newer, or&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;the dependency on Atmosphere to 0.9.5 (0.9.6 and 0.9.7 are broken as well)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href='https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/WICKET-4656'&gt;WICKET-4656&lt;/a&gt; for more information regarding this issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id='this_release'&gt;This release&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the roadmap with a list of the major goals: &lt;a href='https://cwiki.apache.org/WICKET/wicket-60-roadmap.html'&gt;6.0 roadmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;And the migration guide with all major and some minor changes between 1.5.x and 6.x series: &lt;a href='http://s.apache.org/wicket-6.0-migration'&gt;migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Jira changelog of all closed ticket at Jira: &lt;a href='http://s.apache.org/wicket-6.0.0-beta3-changelog'&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use it in Maven:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.apache.wicket&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;wicket-core&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;6.0.0-beta3&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t use a dependencies management build tool then you can download the full distribution (including source) and build from source yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wicket team!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wicket Native WebSockets support</title>
   <link href="http://wicket.apache.org/2012/06/20/wicket-native-websockets.html"/>
   <updated>2012-06-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://wicket.apache.org/2012/06/20/wicket-native-websockets</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new experimental module just landed in Wicket&amp;#8217;s Git repository - Wicket Native WebSocket. It provides the support for HTML5 WebSockets in Wicket as the one for Ajax that you may already use in your applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full documentation is available at &lt;a href='https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/x/0vSoAQ'&gt;Native WebSocket Wiki&lt;/a&gt; A demo application is available at &lt;a href='https://github.com/martin-g/wicket-native-websocket-example'&gt;Martin Grigorov&amp;#8217;s GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any feedback about the new module, its implementation and its documentation is very welcome! Just ask your question in Wicket&amp;#8217;s mailing lists or IRC channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wicket team!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wicket 1.5.7 released</title>
   <link href="http://wicket.apache.org/2012/06/04/wicket-1.5.7-released.html"/>
   <updated>2012-06-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://wicket.apache.org/2012/06/04/wicket-1.5.7-released</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the seventh maintenance release of the Wicket 1.5.x series. This release brings over 26 bug fixes and improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf/wicket/repo?p=wicket.git;a=shortlog;h=refs/tags/wicket-1.5.7'&gt;Git tag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12310561&amp;amp;version=12321241'&gt;Changelog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To use in Maven:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='xml'&gt;&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;org.apache.wicket&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;wicket-core&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;1.5.7&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the &lt;a href='http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/wicket/1.5.7'&gt;full distribution&lt;/a&gt; (including source)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wicket 6.0.0-beta2 released</title>
   <link href="http://wicket.apache.org/2012/05/29/wicket-6.0.0-beta2-released.html"/>
   <updated>2012-05-29T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://wicket.apache.org/2012/05/29/wicket-6.0.0-beta2-released</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Wicket team is proud to announce the second beta release of the Wicket 6.x series. This release brings over many improvements over the 1.5.x series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='new_and_noteworthy'&gt;New and Noteworthy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id='wicket_atmosphere'&gt;Wicket Atmosphere&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Beta 2 contains a new experimental module Wicket Atmosphere, which brings serverside push to Wicket and provides a great way to render serverside markup and send it to the browsers of your users. Check out the atmosphere example in our Examples project to see it in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your application&amp;#8217;s init method you need to register the push event bus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='java'&gt;&lt;span class='k'&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nf'&gt;EventBus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='k'&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere where you want to push your changes to the client, you need to publish your event to the push &lt;code&gt;EventBus&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='java'&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;EventBus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='na'&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='na'&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='na'&gt;getModelObject&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;());&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally you need to subscribe your page (or component) to the &lt;code&gt;EventBus&lt;/code&gt;&amp;#8217;s events with &lt;code&gt;@Subscribe&lt;/code&gt;, taking in the typed parameter you post to the EventBus (in this case a &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='java'&gt;&lt;span class='nd'&gt;@Subscribe&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='kd'&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='kt'&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nf'&gt;receiveMessage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;AjaxRequestTarget&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;target&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class='n'&gt;label&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='na'&gt;setDefaultModelObject&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class='n'&gt;target&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='na'&gt;add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;label&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='o'&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be able to use Wicket Atmosphere you need to include the following dependency:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='xml'&gt;&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;org.apache.wicket&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;wicket-atmosphere&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;0.1&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that this is still experimental.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='this_release'&gt;This release&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check the &lt;a href='https://cwiki.apache.org/WICKET/wicket-60-roadmap.html'&gt;roadmap&lt;/a&gt; with a list of the major goals. And the &lt;a href='https://cwiki.apache.org/WICKET/migration-to-wicket-60.html'&gt;migration guide&lt;/a&gt; with all major and some minor changes between 1.5.x and 6.x series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jira changelog of all closed ticket at &lt;a href='https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12310561&amp;amp;version=12320343'&gt;Jira&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use it in Maven:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='xml'&gt;&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;org.apache.wicket&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;wicket-core&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;6.0.0-beta2&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;#8217;t use a dependencies management build tool then you can download the &lt;a href='http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/wicket/6.0.0-beta2'&gt;full distribution&lt;/a&gt; (including source).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no more planned API breaks but if you find something that can be made better now it the time to discuss it! We will try to avoid making any API changes in the Release Candidates that will follow this beta release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any feedback about the new features, their implementation and their documentation is very welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wicket team!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wicket 1.5.6 released</title>
   <link href="http://wicket.apache.org/2012/05/07/wicket-1.5.6-released.html"/>
   <updated>2012-05-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://wicket.apache.org/2012/05/07/wicket-1.5.6-released</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the sixth maintenance release of the Wicket 1.5.x series. This release brings over 40 bug fixes and improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf/wicket/repo?p=wicket.git;a=shortlog;h=refs/tags/wicket-1.5.6'&gt;Git tag&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12310561&amp;amp;version=12319053'&gt;Changelog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To use in Maven:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='xml'&gt;&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;org.apache.wicket&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;wicket-core&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;1.5.6&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the &lt;a href='http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/wicket/1.5.6'&gt;full distribution&lt;/a&gt; (including source)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wicket 6.0.0-beta1 released</title>
   <link href="http://wicket.apache.org/2012/03/26/wicket-6.0.0-beta1-released.html"/>
   <updated>2012-03-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://wicket.apache.org/2012/03/26/wicket-6.0.0-beta1-released</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Wicket team is proud to announce the first beta release of the Wicket 6.x series. This release brings over many improvements over the 1.5.x series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check the &lt;a href='https://cwiki.apache.org/WICKET/wicket-60-roadmap.html'&gt;roadmap&lt;/a&gt; with a list of the major goals. And the &lt;a href='https://cwiki.apache.org/WICKET/migration-to-wicket-60.html'&gt;migration guide&lt;/a&gt; with all major and some minor changes between 1.5.x and 6.x series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jira changelog of all closed ticket at &lt;a href='https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=12310561&amp;amp;version=12319052'&gt;Jira&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use it in Maven:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='xml'&gt;&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;org.apache.wicket&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;wicket-core&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;6.0.0-beta1&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='nt'&gt;&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;#8217;t use dependencies management build tool then you can download the &lt;a href='http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/wicket/6.0.0-beta1'&gt;full distribution&lt;/a&gt; (including source).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no more planned API breaks but if you find something that can be made better now it the time to discuss it! We will try to avoid making any API changes in the Release Candidates that will follow this beta release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any feedback about the new features, their implementation and their documentation is very welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wicket team!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>CVE-2012-1089 - Apache Wicket serving of hidden files vulnerability</title>
   <link href="http://wicket.apache.org/2012/03/22/wicket-cve-2012-1089.html"/>
   <updated>2012-03-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://wicket.apache.org/2012/03/22/wicket-cve-2012-1089</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Vendor: The Apache Software Foundation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Versions Affected: Apache Wicket 1.4.x and 1.5.x&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description: It is possible to view the content of any file of a web application by using an Url to a Wicket resource which resolves to a &amp;#8216;null&amp;#8217; package. With such a Url the attacker can request the content of any file by specifying its relative path, i.e. the attacker must know the file name to be able to request it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mitigation: Setup a custom org.apache.wicket.markup.html.IPackageResourceGuard that provides a whitelist of allowed resources. Since versions 1.4.20 and 1.5.5 Apache Wicket uses by default org.apache.wicket.markup.html.SecurePackageResourceGuard with a preconfigured list of allowed file extensions. Either setup SecurePackageResourceGuard with code like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='java'&gt;&lt;span class='kd'&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='kd'&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nc'&gt;MyApp&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='kd'&gt;extends&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;WebApplication&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='kd'&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='kt'&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nf'&gt;init&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class='kd'&gt;super&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='na'&gt;init&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class='n'&gt;SecurePackageResourceGuard&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;guard&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='k'&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;SecurePackageResourceGuard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class='n'&gt;guard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='na'&gt;addPattern&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;(...);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class='n'&gt;guard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='na'&gt;addPattern&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;(...);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class='n'&gt;getResourceSettings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='na'&gt;setPackageResourceGuard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;guard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='o'&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='o'&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or upgrade &lt;a href='http://wicket.apache.org/2012/03/12/wicket-1.4.20-released.html'&gt;Apache Wicket 1.4.20&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href='http://wicket.apache.org/2012/03/12/wicket-1.5.5-released.html'&gt;Apache Wicket 1.5.5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit: This issue was discovered by Sebastian van Erk.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
</feed>
